Janio Silva

Bachelor and MsC in Computer Science. Blockchain Researcher Objective: Solid Blockchain Career/ZK dev/ZK and Cryptography researcher





janio.r.silva





GENERAL SKILLS

- → BSc in Computer Science (2013) and MSc in Computer Science (2016). From 2003 to 2010, I worked for American Express Brasil until 2008, with the Backoffice and Anti-Fraud department.
- → From 2008 to 2016, I worked as a Developer and Database Developer at companies such as Tribanco (Martins Group) and Federal University of Uberlandia.
- → Since 2016, I have served as an Assistant Professor in Computer Science, focusing on teaching and research.
- → Passionate about blockchain, I am a good builder and smart contract auditor.
- → Proficient in various Ethereum Improvement Proposals (EIPs) such as EIP2535 and others.
- → Familiar with tokens including ERC20, ERC721, and ERC1155.
- → Well-versed in EVM-based chains and actively expanding knowledge to include zero-knowledge layer two solutions like Starknet, utilizing the Cairo language reminiscent of Rust.
- → Started my journey in the Web3 space as a Smart Contract Developer for DeFi projects and freelancing as a Smart Contracts Auditor on Code4rena.
- → Currently engaged in independent Security Research and Audits.
- → Extensive expertise in Linux Servers, Network Administration, Firewall management, Docker, Git, and other essential DevOps practices.
- → Adept at crafting comprehensive test suites to ensure the robustness and reliability of developed solutions.
- → Strong Communication Skills characterized by clarity, conciseness, and professionalism, ensuring effective message delivery.
- → Proficient in LaTeX. It is a good tool to write reports and research

GOALS

· Cryptography Researcher, ZK developer, Blockchain Developer: Build a solid Blockchain/ZK/Cryptography career.

Although I have a strong emphasis towards the technical background, I also have the foundations for banking, security, great communication and implementing cultural and protocol changes. • I am currently doing research on ZK and Cryptography, area where I will start a PhD soon.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Start - End 2004 - 2010	Role Developer and	Company American Express	Technology SQL Server, .NET,
2008 - 2009 2009 - 2011	Database Designer Database Developer DevOps	Tribanco (Martins) GoVoip (Romen)	JavaScript SQL Server, DB2, Oracle Asterisk, PHP, MySQL,
2011 - 2016	Fullstack Dev	Federal University of Uberlandia	Linux Java, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, Linux, JSF,
2016 - 2022	Professor (Aca- demic)	Federal Institute of Minas Gerais	HTML Java, PostgreSQL, JS, HTML, JSF
2021 - 2022 -	Developer Security Researcher	Learning purpose independent	Solidity, Hardhat, Node.js Solidity, Hardhat, Node.js Truffle, Ethers.js, Cairo

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Proficient:

 Solidity (1+ years)
 Cairo (1 year) • .NET (8+ years), Java (10+ years) • Python (1+ years) Bash Script (10+ years) (3+ years) • PHP (5+) • GIT, Docker & DevOps Automations (1+) • JavaScript and WEB (8+ years) • SQL (8+ years) • Node.js (2+) • Hardhat (1+) • Ethers.js (1+) • Ganache (1+) • Truffle (1+) • Foundry • Slither React.js (1+) • Solidity (1+) Cairo(1+)

Solidity (Advanced Level) • LaTeX • Great DeFi understanding security: • Fiat Cards • Anti Fraud • Security Protocols • Card Security • Fraud Tracking

ZK and applied cryptography expertise:

 Great math background, such as calculus, polynomial problems • ZK proofs • Cairo and Starknet environment • Rust (less than one year)

DATABASES

 PostgreSQL • MySQL • SQL Server

EDUCATION

DeFi Talents Program, 2022 • Frankfurt School of Finance & Management

M.Sc. in Computer Science, **2015** • UFU, Brazil B.Sc. in Computer Science,

2013 • UFF, Brazil

Languages → Portuguese (native)

→ English (fluent spoken and writen, native like)